Danielle Andrews

Software Engineer / U.S. Marine Corps Veteran

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 5+ years of experience in end-to-end full-stack development across startups, mid-sized companies, and open-source projects. 7 years of combined experience in both military and engineering leadership with a background in mechanical engineering and aviation maintenance.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Hack For LA, APRIL 2024 – PRESENT

- Refactored GHA workflows using GraphQL when the website team migrated to the new version of GitHub Projects, improving workflow efficiency by 30%.
- Improved accessibility for the $\underline{311\text{-data}}$ project by implementing zoom controls for the map that comply with WCAG standards.
- Redefined integration with HuggingFace using DuckDB to improve 311-data's app performance when requesting and showing data on the map.
- Updated technical documentation to improve clarity, reducing confusion for new contributors, leading to a 10% reduction in mistakes on Good First Issues and a 5% higher retention rate in new contributors.

Software Engineer at Playpod, JUNE 2023 – SEPTEMBER 2023

- Architected the language globalization feature, resulting in a 95% increase in the product's user base.
- Enhanced app functionality by implementing robust error handling, introducing a cache of profile photos for user selection, and incorporating breadcrumbs for seamless navigation, reducing user drop-off rates by 40%.

Software Engineer at Danielle's Consulting, JUNE 2020 – PRESENT

- Defined statements of work for a diverse client base that ranges from small to midsize companies, serving customers and agencies statewide.
- Developed comprehensive end-to-end solutions for client websites, ranging from static to dynamic sites, focusing on accessibility for a wide range of users.
- Guided clients through the entire development process, troubleshot existing site issues, and provided ongoing support as business needs evolved.
- Recent client examples:
- Tahuva River Vallev Water District
- The Bridge Workforce Training and Development, LLC
- Other projects:
- Cooler Than You HVAC, My Cook Book Recipe Saver, Hood Canal Stargazers APOD, SpaceBattle!, MyDash Extension, and many more.

Engineering Manager at A&E Conveyor Systems, APRIL 2019 – JUNE 2020

- Created and maintained an engineering schedule, resulting in 20% faster project completion.
- Lead engineering projects, using Autodesk Suite, from sales hand-off, through project completion, to customer support.
- Oversaw in-house product fabrication and assembly.
- Managed the mechanical engineering team, while coordinating with internal departments, vendors, and customers, resulting in 95% on-time and in-budget project completion rate.

(770) 355-1281 danielle.andrews.dev@icloud.com danielle-andrews.devdecks.com github.com/DrAcula27 linkedin.com/in/daniellerandrews

SKILL S

Programming Languages

JavaScript, R, YAML, GraphQL, Markdown, HTML, CSS

Libraries & Frameworks

Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MUI, React, jQuery, R-Shiny

Tools & Platforms

MongoDB, DuckDB, AWS S3, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.js, Postman, Git, GitHub, Vercel, Render, GoDaddy, VSCode, VirtualBox

Design

Canva, Figma, Gimp, Adobe Express

Mechanical Engineering

Autodesk Suite, SolidWorks, Tekla Structures, LaTeX

EDUCATION

B. S. Mechanical Engineering

Kennesaw State University

- Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Global Engagement Certification
- Relevant Course: Programming for Engineers (C++)

MILITARY

USMC Veteran

Helicopter Mechanic | Sergeant (E5)

VOLUNTEERING

SciPy Conference 2024

Tacoma, WA

Hood Canal Salmon

Enhancement Group

Field Research & Stewardship

INTERESTS

Smart house: home server, pi-hole ad-sink, home assistant; 3D printing; Discworld; Skyrim